

CONTACT

★ Address Grillenberg 1 3160 Traisen Austria

Phone number +43 68184013023

🕅 Email lisa.hollaus@live.at

GitHub https://github.com/LisaHollaus

SKILLS

Technical:

- Python: OOP, Databases, Networking, Django, Concurrency
- R: Statistics, Visualization
- Web: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node.js, **JavaScript**
- Networking: Cisco Packet Tracer, Wireshark
- Databases: SQLite, SQLAlchemy, neo4j

Analytical:

- Data Analysis
- Project Management
- Organizational Skills

Soft:

- Adaptability
- Communication
- Problem-Solving
- Teamwork
- **Cultural Awareness**

Hollaus Lisa-Maria

Informatics Student

PROFILE

As a passionate student currently pursuing a bachelor's degree in informatics (with a focus on Data Science at IMC University of Applied Science), my background includes not only technical skills and various work experiences, but also a unique 1.5-year period of traveling across Europe, Northern and Central America between 2021 and 2023, enriching my adaptability and broadening my global perspective.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancer

upwork.com

Remote

https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~01f41de3c5d1e4ff81?mp_source=share

- **Search Results Correction**
- Scripted Speech Smartphone Data Collection
- German Solo call

Agricultural worker

Restaurant ('Most-Buschenschank') and organic farm Hollaus Traisen, Austria

www.grillenberg.at

- Production of home-grown juice, sirup, jam, liqueur, schnaps,...
- Food and beverages service

Farm hand

11/2021 - 12/2021

workaway.info

Hegranes, Iceland

- Animal care (sheeps, horses, ducks, cats and dogs)
- Baking and cooking for the family
- Basic household chores

Office Assistant

District Chamber of Farmers

Lilienfeld, Austria

- InfoPoint
- Assistance with Funding applications
- Transferring data; digitization

09/2020 - 09/2023

(inconsistently)

03/2021 - 05/2021

10/2022 - Present

Practical:

- Agriculture & Food Production
- Animal Care
- Childcare & Home Care

LANGUAGES

German (Mother tongue) English (Level C1 – main language at university) Spanish (Beginner)

HOBBIES

- Hiking
- Cooking and Baking
- Travelling
- Learning new skills
- Reading

Confectioner (including apprenticeship)

Bakery Florian Hink Wilhelmsburg, Austria

https://www.florian-hink.at/

Employed in all fields including:

- Basic Austrian sweets production
- Baking and decorating cakes for special events
- Ice-cream production
- Pralines manufacture
- Seasonal work like Christmas cookies,...

INTERNSHIPS

Home care aid

05/2016 – 07/2016

09/2016 - 09/2020

Volkshilfe Traisen & Nursing home Türnitz Austria

- Sustain and support physical, mental and social well-being
- Obtaining the household
- Documentation

Kindergarten Assistant

11/2015

Kindergarten Kirchengasse

Traisen, Austria

- Supporting the kindergarten carer
- Encourage and motivate the children
- Settle disputes

Service

07/2015 - 08/2015

Confectionary Felbermayer

Lilienfeld, Austria

- Taking orders (beverage and food)
- Serve Austrian desserts, ice-cream and coffee variations
- Dealing with bill payments

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

UNIVERSITY

Informatics bachelor's degree program (3. Semester)

IMC University of Applied Science

Krems an der Donau, Austria

Computer Science focused on Data Science

'BERUFSREIFEPRÜFUNG'

09/2017 - 02/2021

2023 - Present

(A-Level - general qualification for university entrance)

Berufsförderungsinstitut (BFI)

St.Pölten, Austria

https://www.bfinoe.at/

Evening-classes

APPRENTICESHIP

Confectioner

Bakery Florian Hink Wilhelmsburg, Austria

https://www.florian-hink.at/

2016 – 2018

TECHNICAL SCHOOL (3 years)

Skilled worker for agriculture- and household-management Fachschule Sooß

Sooß, Austria

Graduating with "Mittlere Reife" (GCSE), as well as:

- ECDL (European Computer Driving License)
- HACCP certificate
- Allergy-training-course
- Kindergarten assistant
- Home-helper
- Medical office assistant with diploma course
- Baby Fit (Babysitter)
- First-aid course

SECONDARY SCHOOL

2009 - 2013

2013 - 2016

Traisen, Austria

ELEMENTARY SCHOOL

2005 - 2009

Traisen, Austria

TRAVEL EXPERIENCE

2021 - 2023

- 14 months long solo travel across northern Europe, Iceland, Northern and Central America
- Engaged in cultural exchanges and intercultural work experiences through 'Workaway'
- 4.5 months long solo walk (pilgrimage) from Austria to Spain in 2023
- Developed strong adaptability, communication, and problem-solving skills through immersion in various environments